

BENJAMIN BOY

Web developer
Front-end

Bordeaux, France

boy.benjamin@proton.me

(a) https://benjamin-boy.netlify.app/

From an original training in the graphic industry to a career change to become a web developer, passionate about music, fond of hiking and surfing, I seek to put my knowledge and my skills to good use.

Being experienced in graphic jobs, I am naturally committing myself to front-end development with the use of css, sass, tailwind, React and other frameworks and libraries on top of good knowledge of Javascript.

SKILLS

Professional

Front-end programming Component-driven workflow Responsive design Managing Rest API Website Design Prototyping

Tech

Javascript
React
Sass
Tailwind CSS
Figma
Strapi
Node Js
Express Js
PostgresQL
GraphQL

EDUCATION

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

O'CLOCK - 2022

Already code enthousiast, I chose a new career path as a web developer by following the Full-stack developer training at O'clock for six months during which I was able to learn the essential skills to become a successful web developer.

GRAPHIC ARTIST IN 3D ANIMATION AND VISUAL EFFECTS

ESMA/Ecole supérieure des métiers artistiques - 2010

Passionate about art, I wanted to take this appetency further by learning about 3D animation and visual effects and becoming a graphic artist.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CONTENT MANAGER

Веемооч - 2016 - 2022

For more than five years I worked as a content manager at Beemoov, video game studio based in Nantes, France.

My main role within the company was to support scriptwriters, developers, graphic artists and marketing people by offring various skills such as compiling content into an administration tool, grood writing, javascript programming.

I had the opportunity to read, correct and suggest modifications on scenarios for the games, to create tools to support the content managing and offer dynamyc content record control using Google App Script.

CONTENT WRITER

SYNTHÈSE & MEDIAS - 2014 - 2016

Fond of writing (short stories, fantasy role playing game lore, etc.), I found in this experience the way to combine it whit my interest in global news, politics, economics, etc.

For almost two years, I was in charge of monitoring medias and compiling media from various sources, mostly national, some european/international.

I also got to write many reviews from those articles for different clients such as Carrefour or Renault.

Overall, this experience allowed me to improve my writing skills, reinforce my knowledge in the news and became more thourough, concise and direct in the tasks I am given.

GRAPHIC ARTIST

VARIOUS COMPANIES - 2010 - 2014

With a degree in 3D animation and visual effects, I got the opportunity to work on many feature films, animation movies, series and advertising.

I was given the chance to create various effects such as muzzle flashes, bulletholes. I worked also on many compositing tasks, integrating objects and characters in live footage, creating various moods. I had also the opportunity to use my 3D artist skills for modeling, texturing, animating and lighting 3D scenes for various projects including Bes visual effect Oscar winning movie Life of Pi. With all these experiences, I learned how to work in a team, supporting people, creating quality material. I also improved my organizational skills, working on different tasks at once and became more independant in my decision making and creativity.